Guide to the J. M. Barrie Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
J. M. Barrie collection
1686-1977
1890-1937
GEN MSS 1400
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
49.83
(77 boxes) + 1 art
The J. M. Barrie Collection contains correspondence, writings, and other papers relating to the life and work of the British author and playwright J. M. Barrie. The material was accrued by the Beinecke Library through gifts and purchases in the decades preceding 2011, and assembled into one collection in 2015. Along with correspondence from, to, and about Barrie, and examples of his writings for the theater, serials, and various publishers and audiences, the collection contains images of Barrie and some of his colleagues, artwork and ephemera from publications and theater productions, writings about him by other authors, and objects including his inkwell and his personal key to London's Kensington Gardens.
Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1860-1937
Alvaro, Corrado, 1895-1956
Anderson, Wellwood, 1859-1940
Ashford, Daisy, 1972-
Asquith, Cynthia, Lady, 1887-1960
Bentley, Nicolas, 1907-1978
Beresford, G. C. (George Charles), 1864-1938
Buchel, Charles A.
Caswall Smith, Lizzie, 1870-1958
Chesterton, G. K. (Gilbert Keith), 1874-1936
Coburn, Alvin Langdon, 1882-1966
Crook, John, -1922
Donnison, T. E.
Downey, Thomas, 1897-1950
Dunbar, Janet
Furst, William, 1852-1917
Gillett, Frank, 1874-1927
Hatherell, William, 1855-1928
Hollyer, Frederick, 1837-1933
Komisarjevsky, Theodore, 1882-1954
Lambda, Peter, 1911-1995
MacGeachy, Cora L., 1894-1960
May, Phil, 1864-1903
Moulton, Louise Chandler, 1835-1908
Muirhead, James F. (James Fullarton), 1853-1934
Murfin, Jane, 1892-1955
Nicholson, William, 1872-1949
Norman, George, Mrs.
Partridge, Bernard, 1861-1945
Pielmeier, John
Rackham, Arthur, 1867-1939
Reed, Edward Tennyson, 1860-1933
Ricketts, Charles S., 1866-1931
Saenger, Gustav, 1865-1935
Scott, Peter, 1909-1989
Simpson, Joseph W. (Joseph William), 1878-
Thomson, Hugh, 1860-1920
Artificers' Guild Ltd
Charles Scribner's Sons
Walt Disney Productions
Carter, David Broadfoot, approximately 1878-1946
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The J. M. Barrie Collection is made up of a number of acquisitions. The core of the collection—and its largest component—was accumulated by and given to the library by Walter Beinecke Jr. An overview of this material can be found in Howard S. Mott's article, "The Walter Beinecke, Jr., J. M. Barrie Collection" in the Yale Library Gazette 39, no. 4 (April 1965). After Mr. Beinecke slowed his collecting in the late 1960s, the Beinecke Library continued to add items to the Barrie collection, in some instances with funds provided by Mr. Beinecke and in other instances with monies used to support the General Collection of Modern Books and Manuscripts. Mr. Beinecke gave the library occasional gifts of material up through the 1970s; most of the material acquired after 1980 was purchased directly by the library.
All of the archival material related to J. M. Barrie that came into the library before 2011 has now been gathered into this collection, with the exception of a few prominent acquisitions such as the Llewelyn Davies Family Papers (GEN MSS 554) and the Quiller-Couch Family Papers (GEN MSS 551). Individual donations of material, such as those made to Yale University Library in the 1940s and 1950s from W. Robert Blum (Yale 1916) and Henry C. Taylor (Yale 1917), have been acknowledged in the finding aid, when known.
The printed collection of works by Barrie, also gathered in large part by Walter Beinecke Jr. and which built upon an earlier gift to the library by Mr. Taylor, were described separately in the library's online catalog.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Correspondence, 1686–1955. II. Writings, 1876–1954. III. Other Papers, 1876–1977.
Biographical / Historical
James Matthew Barrie (1860-1937), Scottish author and playwright.
Scope and Contents
The J. M. Barrie Collection contains correspondence, writings, and other papers relating to the life and work of the British author and playwright J. M. Barrie. The material was accrued by the Beinecke Library through gifts and purchases in the decades preceding 2011, and assembled into one collection in 2015. Along with correspondence from, to, and about Barrie, and examples of his writings for the theater, serials, and various publishers and audiences, the collection contains images of Barrie and some of his colleagues, artwork and ephemera from publications and theater productions, writings about him by other authors, and objects including his inkwell and his personal key to London's Kensington Gardens.
Artists -- Great Britain; Authors, English -- 19th century -- Archives; Authors, English -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors, Scottish -- 19th century -- Archives; Authors, Scottish -- 20th Century -- Archives; Costume design -- Great Britain; Dramatists, English; Dramatists, Scottish; English literature -- 19th century; English literature -- 20th Century; Illustrators -- Great Britain; Incidental music -- Scores; Scottish literature -- 19th century; Scottish literature -- 20th Century; String quartets -- Scores; Theater -- Great Britain; Animation cels -- United States -- 20th Century; Autograph albums -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Cabinet photographs -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Caricatures -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Drawings (visual works) -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Drawings (visual works) -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Illustrations (layout features) -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Illustrations (layout features) -- United States -- 20th Century; Inkwells -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Oil paintings (visual works) -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Page proofs -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Photograph albums -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Photograph albums -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Photographs -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Photographs -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Scripts (documents) -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Scores -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Sketchbooks -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Watercolors (paintings) -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Authors -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Authors -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Authors -- Scotland -- 19th century; Authors -- Scotland -- 20th Century; Dramatists -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Dramatists -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Illustrators -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Illustrators -- Great Britain -- 20th Century; Alvaro, Corrado, 1895-1956; Anderson, Wellwood, 1859-1940; Ashford, Daisy ( Mr. Salteena's plan); Asquith, Cynthia, Lady, 1887-1960; Baldwin, Stanley Baldwin, Earl, 1867-1947; Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1860-1937; Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1860-1937 -- Caricatures and cartoons; Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1860-1937 -- Portraits; Bedford, F. D., 1864-1954; Bentley, Nicolas, 1907-1978; Beresford, G. C. (George Charles), 1864-1938; Bergner, Elisabeth, 1897-1986; Boucicault, Dion, 1859-1929; Boucicault, Nina, 1867-1950 -- Portraits; Bright, Reginald Golding, 1875-1941; Buchel, Charles A.; Burlingame, Edward L. (Edward Livermore), 1848-1922; Carlow, George Lionel Seymour Dawson-Damer, Viscount, 1907-1944; Caswall Smith, Lizzie, 1870-1958; Chesterton, G. K. (Gilbert Keith), 1874-1936; Clifford, W. K., Mrs., -1929; Coburn, Alvin Langdon, 1882-1966; Colles, William Morris, 1855-1926; Colvin, Frances Fetherstonhaugh Sitwell, 1839-1924; Colvin, Sidney, 1845-1927; Cooper, Duff, Viscount Norwich, 1890-1954; Crook, John, -1922; Crisp, Donald, 1880-1974; Croxton, Arthur, 1868-; Daniell, Alfred, 1853-1937; Donnison, T. E.; Downey, Thomas, 1897-1950; Dunbar, Janet; Dunn, James Nicol, 1856-1919; Elizabeth, Queen of Great Britain, II, 1926-; Ervine, St. John G. (St. John Greer), 1883-1971; Farren, William, 1853-1937; Frohman, Charles, 1860-1915; Furst, William, 1852-1917; Gillett, Frank, 1874-1927; Gillette, William, 1853-1937; Gillette, William, 1853-1937 -- Portraits; Gilmour, Thomas Lennox, 1859-1936; Gorell, Ronald Gorell Barnes, Baron, 1884-1963; Granville-Barker, Helen, -1950; Hayman, Al, 1852?-1917; Hatherell, William, 1855-1928; Hentschel, Carl, 1864-1930; Herbert, A. P. (Alan Patrick), 1890-1971; Hollyer, Frederick, 1837-1933; Hubback, Edith C. (Edith Charlotte), 1876-; Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936; Komisarjevsky, Theodore, 1882-1954; Lambda, Peter, 1911-1995; Llewelyn Davies family; Llewelyn Davies, George, 1893-1915; Llewelyn Davies, Geraldine Agnes, 1898-1979; Llewelyn Davies, John, 1894-1959; Llewelyn Davies, Michael, 1900-1921; Llewelyn Davies, Michael, 1900-1921 -- Portraits; Llewelyn Davies, Nicholas, 1903-1980; Llewelyn Davies, Peter, 1897-1960; Lucas, Audrey, 1898-1975; Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall), 1868-1938; McCarthy, Lillah, 1875-1960; MacGeachy, Cora L., 1894-1960; McLaren, Jack, 1887-1954; Martin-Harvey, John, Sir, 1863-1944; May, Phil, 1864-1903; Meredith, William Maxse, 1865-1937; Moult, Thomas; Moulton, Louise Chandler, 1835-1908; Muirhead, James F. (James Fullarton), 1853-1934; Murfin, Jane, 1892-1955; Nicholson, William, 1872-1949; Norman, George, Mrs.; Partridge, Bernard, 1861-1945; Payne, Ben Iden, 1881-1976; Phillpotts, Eden, 1862-1960; Pielmeier, John; Pinero, Arthur Wing, 1855-1934; Nicoll, W. Robertson, Sir (William Robertson), 1851-1923; Rackham, Arthur, 1867-1939; Reed, Edward Tennyson, 1860-1933; Reid, T. Wemyss (Thomas Wemyss), 1842-1905; Ricketts, Charles S., 1866-1931; Ritchie, Anne Thackeray, 1837-1919; Rosebery, Archibald Philip Primrose, Earl of, 1847-1929 -- Caricatures and cartoons; Saenger, Gustav, 1865-1935; Scribner, Arthur H.; Scott, Peter, 1909-1989; Shorter, Clement King, 1857-1926; Sichel, Walter, 1855-1933; Simpson, Joseph W. (Joseph William), 1878-; Strong, Austin, 1881-1952; Thomson, Hugh, 1860-1920; Trevelyan, Hilda, 1877-1959; Trevelyan, Hilda, 1877-1959 -- Portraits; Vanbrugh, Irene, 1872-1949; Vanbrugh, Irene, 1872-1949 -- Portraits; Vedrenne, John Eugene, 1867-1930; Vibart, Henry Meredith, 1839-1917; Ward, Humphry, Mrs., 1851-1920; Waters, James, 1860-1923; Watson, Frederick, 1885-1935; Watson, H. B. Marriott (Henry Brereton Marriott), 1863-1921; Artificers' Guild Ltd; Charles Scribner's Sons; Douglas Cockerell & Son (Firm); Hodder and Stoughton; Riviere & Son; Sangorski & Sutcliffe; W.T. Morrell & Co; Walt Disney Productions; Carter, David Broadfoot, approximately 1878-1946
- Correspondence, 1686–1955; Series I; 8.13; 20 boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains more than a thousand letters written by, to, or about J. M. Barrie. Because it was accumulated in a piecemeal fashion, the collection is predominantly composed of letters written by Barrie to his friends and colleagues, nearly all of which are autograph letters, signed (or ALS). In 1920 Barrie lost the use of his right hand and learned to write with his left (see his speech "Hand" in Series II, Box 50). In either hand, his script is exceptionally difficult to read but many of the letters are accompanied by typed transcriptions. Dates on the letters are similarly difficult to decipher, and readers should keep that in mind when comparing entries in the finding aid to the letters themselves.
  Correspondents in the series include social, literary, and theatrical royalty, as well as actual royalty in a letter to Barrie from Queen Elizabeth II, written when she was just 11. Notables include Barrie's literary agent Reginald Golding Bright (with more than 200 letters from Barrie to him), personal friends Thomas Lennox Gilmour (over 250 letters) and Elizabeth and Edward Verrall Lucas, the novelist and playwright H. B. Marriott Watson, and the actresses Elisabeth Bergner, Lillah McCarthy, Hilda Trevelyan, and Irene Vanbrugh. A star of German theater who moved to England in the early 1920s, Bergner was a particular favorite; in addition to Barrie's nearly 100 letters to her in Series I, her script for his last play, The Boy David, which was written especially for her, can be found in Series II.
  The correspondence spectrum also encompasses Barrie's letters to the less-famous, such as Edmund Caley, who wanted to produce crackers featuring quotations from Peter Pan, to Miss Dallas, who was responsible for making changes to Barrie's motion picture film The Cinema Supper at the Savoy, and to two women, Ethel Dickens and Mrs. Gill, who typed his manuscripts. Also in the series is a group of third-party correspondence wherein Barrie, his writings, or his activities were discussed. This subseries holds the collection's earliest item, a 1686 document related to the family of Alfred Daniell, a mutual friend of Barrie and Helen Edwards, his beloved Edinburgh landlady.
  The greatest number of letters in the series, however, are those Barrie wrote to the people closest to him: his secretary, friend, and literary executor Lady Cynthia Mary Evelyn Asquith (1887–1960), a writer, socialite, and daughter of Hugo Richard Charteris, 11th Earl of Wemyss (1857–1937), and the members of the Llewelyn Davies family, in particular the five sons of Arthur (1863–1907) and Sylvia du Maurier Llewelyn Davies (1866–1910), for whom Barrie became a trustee and guardian upon their mother's death. Also present and forming its own subseries is the J. M. Barrie correspondence file from the firm Charles Scribner's Sons, his American publisher, which features more than 1,000 letters and copies of letters written by Barrie, the staff members at Scribner's and at Hodder and Stoughton, his London publisher, and other correspondents.
  Barrie's great popularity led to his regularly being invited to events, parties, and dinners, and the series contains many brief responses (most in the negative) to invitations received or favors asked, such as for parts in productions his plays. Detailed content descriptions and publication information appearing in the finding aid are remnants of the library's early-to-mid-twentieth-century cataloging efforts. Information that had been typed onto catalog cards has been retained, but no enhanced description was provided for material acquired by the library after 1990.
  Filed at the end of the first subseries are a group of letters written by Barrie to recipients who could not be identified. Most are simply addressed to "Dear Sir" or "Dear Madam" but those bearing salutations with any part of a name (such as "Miss Wooten," "Lady Simson," or "Stephen") were filed alphabetically under that name for purposes of discovery.
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into four subseries: Letters from J. M. Barrie, Letters to J. M. Barrie, Charles Scribner's Sons Correspondence, and Third-Party Letters About J. M. Barrie.
  - Letters from J. M. Barrie
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Aberdeen and Temair, John Campbell Hamilton-Gordon, Marquess of, 1904; 1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Academy of Dramatic Art (Great Britain), 1914 May 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adam, Patrick W., 1923; 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adams, Maude, 1917–1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Containing references to Dear Brutus, the filming of Peter Pan, and Thomas Hardy.
    - Adams, Mr., 1891 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Adams, Mrs., 1922 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Adcock, Arthur St. John, 1924; 1927 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Refusing permission for J. A. Hammerton to write his biography, and for permission to reprint "Scotland's Lament" in The Bookman.
    - Aikman, [Charles Morton?], [1903?] Jun 26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Referring to the death of [James?] McMillan.
    - Aldons, B. E., 1933 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Alexander, Florence Jane, 1918; 1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Condolence note to Lady Alexander on the death of her husband George Alexander (1858-1918).
    - Alexander, L. C., 1905; 1909 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      One letter refers to Bret Harte's daughter.
    - Allen, Ellen Jerrard, 1899; 1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Expressing sympathy on the death of her husband Grant, and a refusal to aid in the Golden Valley appeal.
    - Anderson, Wellwood, 1886–1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Letter of June 20, 1903, gift of W. Robert Blum (Yale 1916), 1954.
    - Angus, Mr., 1924 July 26 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Annerley, Frederick, 1907–1911 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Actor in a Peter Pan touring company.
    - Ansell, Mary, 1917 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Arnold, Edward, 1902 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Arthur, Donald, 1920 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Asquith, Cynthia, Lady
      - Letters, 1919–1924 (Box 1, Folder 19-24)
      - Letters, 1925–1932 (Box 2, Folder 25-32)
      - Letters, 1933-1937; undated (Box 3, Folder 33-38)
    - Ashwell, Lena, 1907; [1910?] (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Atkins, Mr., 1904 May 19 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      Replying to a request for a contribution to the Orphans Working School. Enclosure (check for the Orphans Working School) wanting.
    - Authors Syndicate, 1910 March 9 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      Concerning Barrie's use of the title "Old Friends," previously used by Lady Violet Grenville.
    - Baildon, H. Bellyse (Henry Bellyse), 1902; 1903 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Baker, A. Russell, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Baldwin, Lucy, 1930 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Ballantyne, Jane Grant, 1912–1913 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Baring, Maurice, 1927; 1930 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Barnes, Kenneth, 1927–1932 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      Containing references to the Carnegie United Kingdom Trust. Letter dated 1932 was published in Letters of J. M. Barrie, edited by Viola Meynell (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1947).
    - Barrie, Margaret, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Barrie, Mrs., 1926 January 1 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Batley, Dorothy, 1918? (Box 3, Folder 50)
      Replying to a request for a part in one of Barrie's plays.
    - Beacock, George Ashton, 1909 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Bedford, F. D., 1911 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      Nine letters regarding illustrations for Peter Pan; bound in one volume.
    - Bell, Mackenzie, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      Includes one letter from Barrie to Bell, and two letters from Bell to Barrie.
    - Bell, Robert Fitzroy, 1891–1898 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Bennett, Arnold, 1922 November 13 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Benson, Earl Maltby, 1927 September 17 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      Referring to Benson's edition of Moby Dick.
    - Bentley, Richard, 1894–1925 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      Some letters may be to another Mr. Bentley.
    - Bergner, Elisabeth, 1934–1937 (Box 4, Folder 58-59)
      Sixty-one letters, thirty telegrams, and one postcard to the actress.
    - Berry, C. W., 1923–1929 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Bettany, G. T. (George Thomas), 1889 December 6 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Beveridge, John, 1899; 1900 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      Concerning the translation of The Little Minister into Norwegian, by Ingeborg von der Lippe Konow.
    - Birrell, Augustine, 1929–1932 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Bishop, G. W. (George Walter), 1935 (Box 4, Folder 64)
      Concerning a matinee committee in honor of Marie Tempest's jubilee. Accompanied by letters to Bishop from others regarding the event.
    - Bliss, Mr., 1896 March 24 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - "Bloomfield", 1922 July 17 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Boucicault, Dion, 1905–1928 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      Containing references to the 1919-1920 production of Peter Pan and to The Wheel.
    - Boucicault, Nina, 1910; 1912 (Box 4, Folder 68)
      Enclosure wanting (speech written by Barrie for Miss Boucicault to deliver at the Playgoers' Club "Peter Pan Dinner" on December 22, 1912).
    - Boyd, Ernest Augustus, 1933 August 23 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Braithwaite, Miss, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Brennecke, Ernest, 1925 April 5 (Box 4, Folder 71)
      Regarding Thomas Hardy.
    - Brenon, Arthur, 1925 February 17 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      Regarding his photograph, A Kiss for Cinderella, and Mary Pickford.
    - Brett-Smith, H. F. B. (Herbert Francis Brett), 1900 June 7 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Bright, Arthur Addison, 1905 April 5 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Bright, Reginald Golding, 1903–1932; undated (Box 4, Folder 75-80)
      More than 200 letters to Bright, Barrie's literary agent.
    - Brookfield, [Charles Hallam Elton?], 1906 May 13 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Brough, Sydney, 1901 July 19 (Box 5, Folder 82)
      Concerning Brough's portrayal of Valentine Brown in Quality Street.
    - Brown, Curtis, 1935 October 29 (Box 5, Folder 83)
      Requesting that his grandnephew bearing the same name and now in Brown's employ stop writing letters that could be attributed to the author.
    - Browne, Maurice, 1913 July 29 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Buchan, John, 1907 March 9 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Bulloch, John Malcolm, 1919 June 15 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Burrows, Augusta, 1920 May 12 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Caley, Edmund J., 1906–1907 (Box 5, Folder 88)
      Giving permission to Caley to produce "Peter Pan" crackers, and including a list of quotations to be used on the crackers.
    - Calthrop, Dion Clayton, 1907; 1908; undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Campbell, Patrick, Mrs., undated (Box 5, Folder 90)
      Photocopies of twelve autograph letters, signed, to Stella Patrick Campbell, dated November 6, 1898, to August 21, 1926, accompanied by four letters concerning Mrs. Campbell. They may not be reproduced.
    - Canton, Guy D., 1926; 1934 (Box 5, Folder 91)
      Declining to write a foreword to a volume of poems by William Canton.
    - Canton, William and Annie Elizabeth, 1891–1927 (Box 5, Folder 92)
      Concerning the copyright of the American edition of The Little Minister (removed from Good Words, 1891); expressing condolences, and thanks for a book of poems.
    - Capey, Ernest F. H., 1906 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Cardus, Neville, 1927 January 12 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - "Carter", 1892 December 7 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Carter, Huntly, 1907–1930 (Box 5, Folder 96)
      Concerning a play written by Carter, and The Cinema Supper at the Savoy. A draft reply in the hand of Carter is on the back of the May letter. Accompanied by two envelopes addressed to Carter by Barrie.
    - Cassell Company, 1907–1928 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      Contains one letter (1907) and three bank checks cashed by Barrie (1925-1928).
    - Castle, Irene, 1918 November 7 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - "Catherine", 1903 January 22 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Catmur(?), D. G., 1903 January 17 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Cave, Anne Estella Sarah Penfold Mathews, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Cazenove, C. F., 1912 January 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Chambers, R. D., 1905 September 23 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Chappell, Miss, 1909 January 16 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Charrington, Charles, 1893; undated (Box 5, Folder 105)
      Includes letter concerning Barrie's play Becky Sharp, Conan Doyle's play Foreign Policy and Thomas Hardy's play The Three Strangers, produced by Charrington as part of a quintuple bill at Terry's Theatre, June 3, 1893.
    - Charteris, Guy Lawrence and Frances Lucy, 1932; undated (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Charteris, Hugo Richard and Mary Constance Wyndham, 1921–1937 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Chatto and Windus, 1884 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 108)
      Advising the publishers to send letters and newspapers to Walter Besant. Enclosures wanting.
    - Chesterton, Mrs., 1917 November 10 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Cholmondeley, Mary, 1904 March 7 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Cirkman, Mr., 1893 August 1 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - City of London (England), Lord Mayor, 1920 April 3 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Clarence, O. B., 1915 May 29 (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Clarke, Dr., 1897 January 30 (Box 5, Folder 114)
      Acknowledging Clarke as the model for the doctor in Sentimental Tommy.
    - Clarke, E. Holman, undated (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Clemens, Cyril, 1936 October 8 (Box 5, Folder 116)
      Expressing an opinion about A. E. Housman's work.